Farbstein, Leonard; Papers apap245
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
The Leonard Farbstein Papers
1955-1970
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap245
45.95 cubic ft.
Leonard Farbstein was a U.S. Representative from New York. Farbstein was born in New York City on October 12, 1902. He graduated from High School of Commerce, attended City College of New York, attended Hebrew Union Teachers College, and graduated from New York University Law School in 1924. During the World War I, Farbstein served in the United States Coast Guard Reserve and later as vice chairman of the East River Day Camp, a philanthropic organization. Farbstein was a lawyer in private practice. Farbstein served as a member of the New York State Assembly from 1932 through 1956. He was elected as a Democrat to the 85th and the six succeeding Congresses (January 3, 1957-January 3, 1971) before being an unsuccessful candidate for renomination to the 92nd Congress in 1970. Farbstein died on November 9, 1993, in New York, NY and his interment is in Cedar Park Cemetery in Paramus, NJ.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted with the exception of a few folders in the 90th Congress and a few folders in the 91st Congress due to the inclusion of personally identifiable data included within these folders.
Acquisition Information
Leonard Farbstein initially donated his papers to Syracuse University during 1970 and 1974. In 2006, the papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical Sketch
Leonard Farbstein was born on October 12, 1902 in New York City. He graduated from the High School of Commerce. He then attended the City College of New York, as well as Hebrew Union Teachers College. Farbstein served in the United States Coast Guard Reserve during World War I. After his service, he attended and graduated from New York University School of Law in 1924. From there, he began practicing law in New York City. On September 18, 1947, Farbstein married Blossom Langer. The following year, 1948, they had a son named Louis Farbstein.
He became active in the political community of New York, and eventually became an elected member of the New York State Assembly; a position he held from January 1, 1933 to December 31, 1956.
From January 3, 1957 to January 3, 1971, he held office as a Democrat in the 85th, 86th, 87th, 88th, 89th, 90th, and 91st Congresses. Additionally, he became a member of the United States House of Representatives from New York's 19th district during this time. He was politically aligned to President Lyndon B. Johnson's Vietnam War policies. In his attempt at re-nomination in 1970, he was defeated by Bella Abzug.
Farbstein died on November 9, 1993 in New York City. He was interred in Cedar Park Cemetery in Paramus, New Jersey.
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of eight series: 85th Congress, 86th Congress, 87th Congress, 88th Congress, 89th Congress, 90th Congress, 91st Congress, and Congressional Record Inserts. The bulk of the records that are present in this collection can be categorized as legislative materials, such as bills and proposed legislation. Much of the content is also correspondence between Farbstein and his constituents. Broken down by subject, there are also records that are specifically related to Foreign Affairs and various Departments and Committees. Additionally, in series 6 and 7, there are also applications to military academies, requesting Farbstein's sponsorship.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1: 85th Congress, 1956-1958
Series 2: 86th Congress, 1956-1960
Series 3: 87th Congress, 1958-1965
Series 4: 88th Congress, 1955-1965
Series 5: 89th Congress, 1956-1966
Series 6: 90th Congress, 1962-1968
Series 7: 91st Congress, 1963-1970
Series 8: Congressional Record Inserts, 1957-1970
Series 1-7 are arranged alphabetically. Series 8 is arranged chronologically.
New York (State) -- Politics and government.; Politics and Politicians; Public Servants; Clippings(information artifacts); Correspondence; Legislation (legal concepts); New York (N.Y.); United States. Congress. House.; New York (State)--Legislature--Assembly
- The 85th Congress, 1956-1958; 1; .2 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically
  Scope and Contents
  The bulk of series one is made up of legislative actions. There are also newspaper clippings that are related to the Middle East, and other topics. Other records present are correspondence between Farbstein and his constituents.
  - Foreign Affairs Committee Personal Notes, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - H. Con. Res. 158: Concurrent Resolution for Treatment of Jews in Egypt, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - H. Con. Res. 220: Concurrent Resolution for "World Travel Week", 1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - H. Con. Res. 251: Concurrent Resolution for United States, Israeli - Greeting on 10th Anniversary of Israeli Independence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - H. Con. Res. 250: Concurrent Resolution for 1960 as "Visit U.S.A. Year", 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - H.J. Res. 265: Joint Resolution for Ukrainian Independence Day, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - H.J. Res. 307: Joint Resolution for Relief of Certain Aliens, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - H.J. Res. 466: Joint Resolution for Hudson-Champlain Celebration Commission, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - H.R. 3939: A Bill for Revising the Laws Relating to Immigration and Citizenship, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - H.R. 11070: A Bill for Federal Aid- Highway Act of 1956, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - H.R. 12390: A Bill for Railroad Travel Safety, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - H. Res. 311: Resolution for Investigation on Food Additives and Their Effects on Health, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Middle East Crisis Legislation, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Middle East News Clips, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- The 86th Congress, 1956-1960; 2; 1.4 cubic ft.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  The contents within this series are comprised primarily of legislation. Bills, resolutions and proposed legislation are included. There are also documents that are related issues in foreign affairs, as well as correspondence.
  - Foreign Affairs: Africa, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Foreign Affairs: Algeria, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Foreign Affairs: Anti-Semitism, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Foreign Affairs: Atlantic Convention, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Foreign Affairs: Cuba, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Affairs: Far East, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Foreign Affairs: Foreign Affairs Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Foreign Affairs: Foreign Student Orientation Program Assistance Act, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Foreign Affairs: Germany, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Foreign Affairs: Guam, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Foreign Affairs: Israel, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Foreign Affairs: Khrushchev, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Foreign Affairs: Latin America, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Foreign Affairs: Lithuania, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Foreign Affairs: Malta, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Foreign Affairs: Middle East, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Foreign Affairs: Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Foreign Affairs: Near East, 1956; 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Foreign Affairs: Near East Report, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Foreign Affairs: Pakistan, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Foreign Affairs: Panama, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Foreign Affairs: The Philippines, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Foreign Affairs: Psychological Warfare, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Foreign Affairs: Red China, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Foreign Affairs: Russia, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Foreign Affairs: Ukraine, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Foreign Affairs: United Nations, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Foreign Affairs: United States Foreign Trade, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Foreign Affairs: United States Foreign Policy, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Foreign Affairs: 1964 World's Fair, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - H. Con. Res 72: Concurrent Resolution for Establishment of Joint Committee om Intelligence Matters, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - H. Con. Res. 294: Concurrent Resolution for Recognition of the Centennial Anniversary of the Unity of Italy, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - H. Con. Res. 474: Concurrent Resolution for Desecration of Houses of Worship, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - H. Con. Res. 505: Concurrent Resolution for Condemnation of Anti-Semitism, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - H. Con. Res. 506: Concurrent Resolution for Presidential Review of Acts of Anti-Semitism, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - H. Con. Res. 591: Concurrent Resolution for Restoration of Liberties to Jewish People of Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - H. Con. Res. 643: Concurrent Resolution for the Restoration of Freedom to Captive Nations, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - H. J. Res. 11: Joint Resolution for Peace Conference Between the Arab and the States of Israel, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - H. J. Res. 355: Joint Resolution for the Diplomatic Relations Between the United States and the Republics of Ukraine and Byelorussia, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - H. J. Res. 636: Joint Resolution for the Amendment of the Mutual Security Act of 1954, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - H. J. Res. 667: Joint Resolution for the Establishment of the Office of Inter-American Affairs, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - H. J. Res. 779: Joint Resolution for International Conference Between the Free World Nations and the New African Governments, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - H. R. 91: A Bill for Establishment of Department of Civil Defense (Also Contains H. R. 174), 1957; 1959 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - H. R. 92: A Bill for Federal Employees' Compensation Act (Also Contains H. R. 12091), 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - H. R. 93: A Bill for Securities Act of 1933, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - H. R. 94: A Bill for Immigration and Nationality Act (Also Contains H. R. 6536), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - H. R. 95: A Bill for Unemployment Rates, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - H. R. 3295: A Bill for Revisal of Immigration and Citizenship Law, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - H. R. 7500: An Act for Amendment of the Mutual Security Act of 1954, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - H. R. 7774: A Bill for School Lunch Program, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - H. R. 9813: A Bill for Social Security Act, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - H. R. 10382: A Bill for Adjustment of Pay Rates for Federal Government Employees, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - H. R. 11457: A Bill for Authorization of Hon. Albert Morano to Wear Merit Medal, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - H. R. 11510: An Act for Further Amendment of the Mutual Security Act of 1954, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - H. R. 12368: A Bill for Civil Service Retirement Act (Also Contains H. R. 11717), 1956; 1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - H. R. 1246: A Bill for International Claims Settlement Act of 1949, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - H. Res. 21: Resolution for Committee of Foreign Affairs, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - H. Res. 261: Resolution for Suspension of Nuclear Weapons Tests, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - H. Res. 426: Resolution for Atomic Disarmament, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - H. Res. 580: Resolution for Federal Aid Highway Program, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Pending Legislation for Discrimination, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Proposed Legislation for Foreign Affairs, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Proposed Legislation for Social Security, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- The 87th Congress, 1958-1965; 1961-1962; 3; 2 cubic ft.
  This series has been arranged into four sub-series: Correspondence and Memoranda, Legislation, Foreign Affairs, and Departments and Committees. The bulk of the records present in the 87th Congress are correspondence and legislation.
  - Correspondence, 1961-1963
    The content of these records include correspondence and other forms of communication between Farbstein and his constituents.
    - Human Rights Legislation, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "I"-"K" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "L" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Labor Legislation, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "M" Last Names, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Manpower Development and Training Act, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Mc" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Medical Care to the Aged (1 of 3), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Medical Care to the Aged (2 of 3), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Medical Care to the Aged (3 of 3), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Migrant Workers, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Minimum Wage, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "N" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Nuclear Weapons Test, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - "O" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Orphan Adoption, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "P" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Philippine War Damage, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Pillion Resolution, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Postal Employees (1 of 2), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Postal Employees (2 of 2), 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Postal Rates, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Prayer (Supreme Court Decision), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - "R" Last Names, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Railroad, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Request for Legislation, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - "S" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Social Security, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - "T" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Taxes (1 of 2), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Taxes (2 of 2), 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Legislation, 1958-1964
    This sub-series contains legislative materials such as bills, concurrent resolutions, and joint resolutions.
    - "A" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Agriculture, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "B" Last Names, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Billboards, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Blindness in the United States, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "C" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Civil Rights, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Compulsory Health Insurance, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "D" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Democratic Study Group, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "E" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Economy, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - "F" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Federal Employees, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Foreign Freight Forwarders, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - "G" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Gold, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "H" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - H. Con. Res. 9: Concurrent Resolution for Establishment of a Joint Committee on Intelligence Matters, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - H. Con. Res. 228: Concurrent Resolution for Inter-American Treaty of Reciprocal Assistance, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - H. Con. Res. 441: Concurrent Resolution for United Nations Human Rights Commission, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - H. J. Res. 123: Joint Resolution for Authorization of Federal Participation in the New York World's Fair (Also Contains Related Bills), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - H. J. Res. 204: Joint Resolution for Declaring Inauguration Day to be a Holiday, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - H. J. Res. 369: Joint Resolution for Amendment to the Constitution Providing for the Popular Election of President and Vice President of the United States, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - H. J. Res. 421: Joint Resolution for Presentation of Medal of Honor to Commander Alan B. Shepard. Jr., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - H. J. Res. 625: Joint Resolution for the First Sunday to be "Shut-In's Day", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - H. R. 10: Gore Amendments, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - H. R. 1283: A Bill for Social Security Act (1 of 2) (Also Contains Related Bills), 1959; 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - H. R. 1283: A Bill for Social Security Act (2 of 2) (Also Contains Related Bills), 1959; 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - H. R. 1289: A Bill for National Peace Agency (Also Contains H. R. 11511), 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - H. R. 2006: A Bill for Low-Rent Housing (Also Contains H. R. 90), 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - H. R. 2418: A Bill for Amendment of Title 10 of United States Code (Also Contains H. R. 6975), 1959; 1961 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - H. R. 2419: A Bill for Housing Act of 1949 (Also Contains Related Bills), 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - H. R. 2420: A Bill for National System of Interstate and Defense Highways (Also Contains Related Bills), 1959; 1961 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - H. R. 2475: A Bill for Prohibition of Discrimination in Employment (Also Contains H. R. 5619), 1959; 1961 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - H. R. 3268: A Bill for Unemployment in Economically Depressed Areas (Also Contains H. R. 5), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - H. R. 4579: A Bill for Housing Act of 1949, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - H. R. 5346: A Bill for Creation of Department of Urban Affairs, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - H. R. 5527: A Bill for Housing Act of 1949, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - H. R. 5933: A Bill for Amendment of Title 38 of United States Code, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - H. R. 6049: A Bill for Social Security Act, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - H. R. 6295: A Bill for United States Housing Act of 1937, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - H. R. 6325: A Bill for National Housing Act, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - H. R. 6326: A Bill for National Housing Act, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - H. R. 6472: A Bill for Housing Act of 1949, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - H. R. 6473: A Bill for Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - H. R. 6474: A Bill for Establishment of National Citizens Council on Migratory Labor, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - H. R. 6475: A Bill to Provide Grants for Adult Education for Migrant Agricultural Employees, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - H. R. 6476: A Bill to Provide Certain Payments to Assist in Providing Improved Educational Opportunities for Children of Migrant Agricultural Employees, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - H. R. 6477: A Bill to Provide for the Registration of Contractors of Migrant Agricultural Workers, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - H. R. 6478: A Bill for Amendment of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - H. R. 6479: A Bill for Amendment of the Act of June 6, 1933, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - H. R. 6480: A Bill for Amendment of Title 3 of the Public Health Services Act, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - H. R. 6481: A Bill for Amendment of Title 5 of the Social Security Act, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - H. R. 6555: A Bill for Amendment of the Immigration and Nationality Act, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - H. R. 6607: A Bill for Amendment of the United States Housing Act of 1937, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - H. R. 7152: A Bill for Amendment of "An Act to Provide Certain Basic Authority for the Department of the State", 1961 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - H. R. 7680: A Bill to Provide for the Establishment of a Federal Advisory Council on the Arts, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - H. R. 7766: A Bill for New York World's Fair Planning, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - H. R. 7940: A Bill for Establishment of United States Disarmament Agency for World Peace and Security, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - H. R. 8179: A Bill for Internal Revenue Code of 1954, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - H. R. 4147: A Bill for Establishment of Hospital Facilities for Narcotic Addicts, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - H. R. 9690: A Bill for Establishment of a Western Hemisphere Police Force, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - H. R. 10491: A Bill for Authorization of United Nations Bonds Purchase, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - H. R. 10492: A Bill for Amendment of Peace Corps Act, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - H. R. 10516: A Bill for Protection Against Arbitrary Discrimination in Federal Elections, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - H. R. 10567: A Bill for United States Housing Act of 1937, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - H. R. 10589: A Bill for Postal Employee Pay, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - H. R. 10703: A Bill for Amendment of Peace Corps Act, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - H. R. 11063: A Bill for Commercial Communications Satellite System, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - H. R. 11316: A Bill for Desegregation of Public Schools, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - H. R. 12028: A Bill for Immigration and Nationality Act, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - H. R. 12172: A Bill for Issuance of Visas for Aliens Residing in Hong Kong Who are Relatives of United States Citizens, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - H. R. 12197 A Bill for Lower Manhattan Expressway (1 of 2) (Also Contains Related Bills), 1958-1962 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - H. R. 12197: A Bill for Lower Manhattan Expressway (2 of 2) (Also Contains Related Bills), 1958-1962 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - H. R. 12360: A Bill for Domestic Peace Corps Aid for Juvenile Delinquency (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - H. R. 12686: A Bill for Federal Aid for Special Education, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - H. Res. 387: Resolution for Establishment of a Special Committee on the Captive Nations, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - H. Res. 458: Resolution for National System of Interstate and Defense Highways, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - H. Res. 459: Resolution for National System of Interstate and Defense Highways, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - H. Res. 465: Resolution for Authorization of Investigation Conducted by Committee Created by H. Res. 458, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - H. Res. 593: A Resolution for United Nations Security Council, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Health, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Housing, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Housing: Battery Park, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Housing: Lower Manhattan Trade Center, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Housing: Washington Square Park, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Proposed Legislation, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Proposed Legislation for Consumers Bill, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Proposed Legislation for Foreign Affairs, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Proposed Legislation for Housing, 1961; 1964 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Proposed Legislation for Mutual Security, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Proposed Legislation for Social Security, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Trade, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Unemployment, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - United Nations Issue, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - "V" Last Names, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Veterans, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "W" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Water Pollution, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - World's Fair 1964, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Youth Conservation Corporation, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "X"- "Z" Last Names, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Foreign Affairs, 1959-1965
    Documentation on certain foreign affairs is contained within this sub-series.
    - Act for International Development of 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Africa, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alaska, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Angola, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Anti-Semitism, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Arab Boycott, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Assembly of Captive European Nations, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Berlin, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - British Guiana, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - China, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Common Market, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Congo, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Cuba, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Egypt, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Foreign Affairs Committee, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Hungary, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - ICA Procurement Bulletin, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - International Relations, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Israel (1 of 2), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Israel (2 of 2), 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 20)